# Alicia Fennell

# Master's Student in Environmental Science & Management

#### About me

I'm a passionate environmental professional focused on climate change solutions, effective environmental communication, and responsible data analysis and visualization. I am a detail-oriented team player with managerial experience and a commitment to learning and growing.

#### Education

2019-2021 Master of Environmental Science and Management, Bren School of Environmental Science & Management, University of California, Santa Barbara, Santa Barbara, CA.

2010-2014 Bachelor of Arts, University of California, Santa Cruz, Santa Cruz, CA.

## — Highlighted Coursework

- Data: Statistics & Data Analysis for Environmental Science & Management, Advanced Data Analysis, Geographic Information Systems (GIS)
- Economics, Law, & Policy: Economics and Policy of Climate Change, Economics of Environmental Management, Environmental Law and Policy, Environmental Politics and Policy, Cost-Benefit Analysis and Non-market Valuation
- Communication: Writing Skills for Environmental Professionals, Advanced Environmental Communication, Survey Design and Environmental Public Opinion, Equity and the Environment
- Energy & Climate: Energy, Technology and the Environment, Climate Change Impacts and Adaptation, Earth System Science, Life Cycle Assessment (LCA)

# Master's Group Project

2020-2021 Evaluating the climate mitigation potential of natural and working lands in Santa Barbara County, Client: County of Santa Barbara, Sustainability Division. Roles: Co-data manager, co-outreach manager, Our team estimated county-wide carbon stocks and nitrous oxide emissions, projected land use change in working lands to create a baseline scenario, modeled forecasted changes to carbon stocks and emissions through land management scenarios, engaged with local experts, and recommended realistic greenhouse gas reduction strategies to the County.

#### Professional Experience

- 2020 Research & Engagement Intern, Santa Barbara County Food Action Network, Santa Barbara, CA.
- 2019-2020 **Teaching Assistant (Sociology & Biology)**, University of California, Santa Barbara, Santa Barbara, CA.
- 2015-2019 Environmental Educator/Naturalist, Exploring New Horizons Outdoor School, Loma Mar, CA.
  - 2018 **Director**, Life Lab Summer Camp, Santa Cruz, CA.
  - 2017 Ecuador Trip Co-Leader, The Road Less Traveled, Ecuador.
- 2015-2016 Assistant Director, Life Lab Summer Camp, Santa Cruz, CA.
- 2014-2015 Naturalist Intern, Sierra Outdoor School, Sonora, CA.

### Additional Experience

- 2017-2019 Community Volunteer, Puente de la Costa Sur, Pescadero, CA.
- 2017-2019 Conference Organizer, Pescadero Valley Conference, Loma Mar, CA.
- 2015-2019 Ropes Course Facilitator, YMCA Camp Jones Gulch, La Honda, CA.

#### Skills and Certifications

- Computer & Software: Microsoft Office Suite (Excel, PowerPoint, Word), Google Workspace, R and RStudio, ArcGIS, Slack, Zoom, Trello
- Language: Spanish (verbal and written proficiency), English fluency
- Certifications: Wilderness First Responder, California Naturalist Program (2014)